Gregory Gasowski

New York, NY

516-301-0472; gregory.gasowski@gmail.com; linkedin.com/in/gregorygasowski

Summary

Experienced manager and architect managing medium to large projects, responsible for delivering digital transformation architectures to key global business and infrastructure initiatives. Responsible for managing and coordinating digital and business projects on premise and cloud infrastructure architectures laaS, PaaS, SaaS, analyzing and designing application, and facilitating productive relationships with business and IT partners on all levels. Many years of technological innovation experience with industries such as pharmaceuticals, ecommerce and non-profit organization, MS certified, enterprise solution architect. Managed technical teams supporting a diverse range of business processes and applications Experienced in Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML) and Distributed Ledger Technology

Managerial skills

- Project lifecycle management and project scheduling
- Requirements definition, analysis and quality assurance
- Project budgeting and cost controls
- Enterprise Implementations and system migrations
- Manage teams of IT professionals, encouraged team development
- Provide leadership and mentorship
- Establish policies and procedures and oversee the implementations of new technologies

Technology Summary

- Office365, SharePoint Server 2016-2007, SP Online, Azure
- Azure services IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS, IoT
- Project Server, PowerShell, Visio, Excel, Power BI
- Data Migration
- AD, SQL
- Azure ML, Google Colab, IBM Watson ML
- Python, JupyterLab, Notebook, Spyder
- TOGAF, Gartner, ITIL, Agile
- Nintex, Metalogix, ShareGate, JIRA

Professional Experience

WaveMax LLC, New York, NY

Owner-Entrepreneurship

Jan 2017 - present

- Designed, built and launched the enterprise cryptocurrency exchange ex.wavemax.com
- Created, built, and launched the enterprise reseller site with domains names, web hosting, SSL and security, and other marketing and ecommerce features wavemaxsolutions.com.
- Advancing knowledge in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.
- Analytical Factor Supported SharePoint content management, security groups, search, improved users' collaboration and communications via implementation of OneDrive and Yammer Implemented B2B hybrid configuration SharePoint 2016 on prem and SharePoint online with Office365 with emphasis on Teams.

Gregory Gasowski

New York, NY

516-301-0472; gregory.gasowski@gmail.com; linkedin.com/in/gregorygasowski

Rollease Acmeda, Stamford, CT

Senior SharePoint Architect

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

- Redesigned and reconfigured SharePoint enterprise infrastructure.
- Provided guidance to enable integration with OneDrive and Yammer for better collaboration and communication to leverage existing SharePoint sites for standardizing user experience.
- Created and configured the enterprise search and e-discovery of structured content using metadata.
- Fostered Office365 tools for increased collaboration within the enterprise leading to productivity gains for employees using OneDrive, Outlook groups and Yammer, trained users.
- Replaced outdated intranet shared public drives with Office365 content management platform.
- Organized modern sites with hub sites for better improved collaboration based on project, department, region.
- Defined SharePoint governance and standards for collaboration and management content.

Analytical Factor, Plainview, NY

Senior SharePoint Architect

Jan 2016 - August 2016

- Established a digital strategy plan and drive the execution.
- Estimated cost saving strategy using Azure TCO
- Forecast profitability of digital transformation Azure ROI
- Designed, installed and configured SharePoint 2016 infrastructure with Office365
- Reviewed workloads, system dependencies, business requirements and security requirements to enhance enterprise infrastructure system reliability, availability, and serviceability
- Prepared capacity and architecture plan to create the Azure Cloud environment to host migrated laaS VMs and PaaS role instances for refactored applications and databases.
- · Implemented a structured design hybrid cloud architecture
- Set up and configured sites in SP2013 with content management and metadata.
- · Migrated AD accounts and sites to SP online
- · Created and configured enterprise federated hybrid search.

Allergan (formerly Forest Labs), New York, 2003–2015

Sr. Systems Architect/Manager

- Managed and delivered high-quality IT architectural enterprise systems and infrastructure designs
 to support architecture initiatives to drive service delivery, optimize cost and support established
 business goals.
- Work with business and IT leaders to ensure the application architecture is internally aligned with corporate strategy, innovation programs, product development, customer initiatives, regulatory matters and other strategic priorities.
- Forecast profitability of digital transformation and platform integration ROI
- Managed IT steering committee and governance board and created governance plan, policies and procedures, code review, roles and responsibilities, information architecture.
- Work with all levels of business and IT to capture and analyze business drivers to develop enterprise application architecture requirements.
- Defined and document current and future state application architectures, frameworks and roadmaps.
- Established digital transformation strategy, setup goals, inspiring and motivating others, and drive the execution.
- Define, implement, and promote application and software architectural guidelines/standards, best practices, governing mechanisms, key processes, controls and supporting tools.

Gregory Gasowski

New York, NY

516-301-0472; gregory.gasowski@gmail.com; linkedin.com/in/gregorygasowski

- Promoted and evangelize shared application services to encourage reuse, reduce costs and improve information flows.
- Designed and build / lead teams to build shared framework components that can be used as reference solutions and/or accelerators for teams to develop.
- Managed vendor rationalization to improve efficiency in development and support applications by analysis of total cost assessment and value optimization of services cost.
- · Performed capacity analysis, planning and design of SharePoint farm and content migration.
- Analyzed and evaluated cloud solutions and set standards for both adoption and usage patterns.
- Partnered with application development teams to ensure that solutions align to reference architecture model and technology strategy.
- Reviewed technology-related investment proposals and verify accurate application solution estimates are provided, proposals are consistent with software architectural guidelines/standards, and potential risks have been identified and estimated cost saving strategy and compared different TCO calculators
- Lead cross-functional teams on software and application technology selection, design considerations, evaluation criteria, due diligence requirements, proofs of concept and any other related software technology selection and adoption techniques.
- Participate as an integral member of the IT management team responsible for defining and implementing software technology strategy, capital plans and continuous improvement objectives.
- Serve as steward and advisor on information assets, software technology environment, solution capabilities, emerging technologies, governance and secure coding practices.

Motivators Inc. Hicksville, NY

Ecommerce Sr. Developer

2001 to 2003

- Coordinated, developed, and maintained ecommerce websites with developing team.
- Designed architecture and developed navigational structures and functionality, usability, accessibility, integration with shopping cart and ordering process.

Cybertech Internet Solutions, Port Washington, NY 1998 to 2001

Solution Architect

- Head of the design department for this full ISP Corporation.
 Responsible for the development of the Corporate Enterprise Architecture (ITSM).
- Established corporate governance, processes, and infrastructure.

Education

- MBA Doane University- Data Analytics/Big Data Emphasis 2020
- Pursuing Microsoft Professional Program for Artificial Intelligence
- IBM Certified Professional in Deep Learning 2019
- MIT Certified: Probability The Science of Uncertainty 2019
- MIT Designing Efficient Deep Learning Systems 2018
- Stanford University on Coursera Machine Learning by 2018
- MIT Certified: Cybersecurity: Technology, Application and Policy 2017
- MIT Certified: Internet of Things: Roadmap to a Connected World 2017
- MCSD.NET Certified (Transcript ID (870820)
- MCP Microsoft Certified Professional
- MS in Physical Education